RAN COHEN

Information



Address Ramat Gan

Israel



Phone +972-54-7998393



Email

Aharonran7@gmail.com



Website

github.com/RoniRan542

Social



LinkedIn

ran-cohen-a0511441

ABOUT ME

Autodidact, hardworking and highly motivated software engineer with practical development experience in *Linux*, *C*, *C++*, *Python*, *Java and JavaScript*. In addition, I have practical experience in databases and data analysis tools such as *R*, *MATLAB and SQLite*. I am a dedicated and internally motivated worker, creative thinker, and a problem-solver. With strong interpersonal skills, I am able to work independently while remaining a team player.



EXPERIENCE

09/2018 - 09/2021

THE HEBREW UNIVERSITY

Jerusalem

Web Developer

Developing independently a website for Gati's lab at the Hebrew University. Working with all aspects of the website life cycle.

01/2019 - 08/2021

THE HEBREW UNIVERSITY

Researcher & Lab manager

Jerusalem

Research in cognitive and brain sciences at HUJI while running a lab,

managing logistics and research plans.

08/2017 - 09/2018

BEIT PRAT

Jerusalem

Logistics

Providing logistic planning and executing quality routines for a nonprofit

organization.

03/2016 - 09/2016

VATBOX

Hertzelia

Data cleansing

Screening valuable data for the Vatbox software application.



EDUCATION

2022 - 2022

INFINITYLABS BOOTCAMP

Successfully completed intensive 8 months of software engineering training program, gaining practical development experience in C and C++ on linux environment, with focus on memory management, system programming, network and multi-threading. I also gained deep understanding of OOD and OOP, design patterns and data structures.

2018 - 2021

THE HEBREW UNIVERSITY - M.A.

Masters in cognitive and brain sciences.

Thesis subject: learning from punishments and the interaction with mood

fluctuations (GBA: 89).

2015 - 2016

JOHN BRYCE COLLEGE

Basics of Java programming, object-oriented concepts, as well as

producing a server web application.

2011 - 2014

BAR ILAN UNIVERSITY - B.A

Bachelors degree in philosophy (major) and history (GBA: 90).

In addition, during this time, I took courses in logic, algorithmic thinking,

and web programming.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Proficiency in C and C++
- Solid foundation in software development fundamental: Data Structure, Design Patterns, Object-Oriented programming, System programming, Multithreading and algorithms.
- Good working knowledge in JavaScript, Python and Java as well as shell scripting in Linux.
- Experience in building Restful APIs with Flask and NodeJs.
- Good knowledge of integration, debugging & testing tools (git ,gdb, valgrind, vscode)
- Good background in databases data manipulation tools (R, matlab, MySQL, SQLite, sqlalchemy)

MILITARY SERVICE

Israel Defence Force, Infantry (Givaty platoon 2006-2009)

LANGUAGES

Hebrew: Native Language. English: Excellent.